不得不说 你可真有种啊
I have to say I was impressed.
你竟敢
You had taken a risk.
跟我对着干
Getting your hands dirty.
你知道吗 那些行尸
You know, we were gonna have those biters.
本来是给米琼恩留的
for our little Michonne and…
那些行尸 你是给所有活人留的
You were gonna use them on whoever showed up.
没错
That's right.
但你却放火
Because we didn't have them,
把它们全烧了
you burned them up,
害死了我八名手下
eight of my men died.
死的人你都认识
Now, you knew those men. Huh?
他们保你安全 供你吃穿
They kept you safe, kept you fed.
只要我睁一只眼闭一只眼就行
As long as I looked the other way.
但不想再像以前了
Well, it can't be like that anymore.
你该有点长进了
Time for you to graduate.
我告诉你末世的生存秘诀
I'm gonna tell you the secret.
有人威胁你的安全 就干掉他
There's a threat, you end it.
不用有愧疚感 尽情享受杀戮
And you don't feel ashamed about enjoying it.
你能闻到弹药味 看到血液
You smell the gunpowder and you see the blood…
知道这说明什么吗
you know what that means?
说明你还活着
It means you're alive.
说明你是赢家
You've won.
你给我牢牢记住
You take the heads so that you don't ever forget.
要么杀死别人 要么你自己死
You kill or you die.
你女儿的在天之灵
What would your daughter think.
会怎么想
about what you are?
她会畏惧我
She'd be afraid of me.
但如果我一开始就这样
But if I had been like this from the start,
说不定她现在还活着
she'd be alive today.
你把安德里亚杀了吗
Did you kill Andrea?
米尔顿
Milton.
看吧 她还活着
See? She's still alive.
留着她还有用
I'm gonna need her for something.
我听见你在旁边屋说的话了
I heard you in the other room.
你不需要再牺牲自己的人了
You don't have to lose any more of your men.
只要你停手
Just stop this.
你监狱里的那些朋友
Your friends at the prison…
我要把他们都杀光
I'm gonna kill them all.
大家都会帮我的
People are gonna help me.
我稍微夸大了点事实 就一点点
I had to stretch the truth a little bit, but just a little.
现在大家都怒火冲天
Now they're foaming at the mouth.
你把那些工具拿来
You, get those tools.
我不需要了
I'm not gonna need them anymore.
快去
Go on.
仔细点 把那个捡起来
Careful. Pick that up.
快点 别磨蹭了 快拿过来
Come on! Step to. Let's go.
等等
Hold up.
我需要这个
I'll take that.
放下
Put 'em down.
你现在去把她杀了
You're gonna kill her now.
以实际行动告诉我你有长进了
You're gonna show me that you've learned something.
米尔顿
Milton…
你不下手的话
there is no way you are leaving this room.
就别想离开这间屋子
without doing it.
别让我为难 你就
So don't make it hard. Just…
杀了她就行了
just do it.
这就对了
That's it.
让你做 你不做
I told you you were gonna do it.
现在你就是死路一条
And now you're gonna die.
死后你会变成行尸
And you're gonna turn.
你会生生地撕下她的肉
And you're gonna tear the flesh from her bones.
现在这个世界
In this life now,
要么杀死别人 要么你自己死
you kill or you die.
或者你死了 再咬死别人
Or you die and you kill.
《行尸走肉》
卡尔
Carl.
从来没见过他这么生气
I've never seen him this mad.
洛莉去世时他也没这样
Even with Lori.
完全把自己封闭起来
He just shut down.
我们很容易忘记
He's still a kid.
他还是个孩子
It's easy to forget.
莫尔这辈子也没做这样的事
You know, Merle never did nothing like that his whole life.
他给了我们一个机会
He gave us a chance.
我们准备好了
We're ready.
总督提出的关于我的交易
The deal the Governor offered about me…
你当时必须得考虑
you had to think about it.
你必须考虑 我理解
You had to. I get it.
对不起 我差一点就同意了
I'm sorry. I came real close.
但是你没有
But you didn't.
我从未谢过你
I never thanked you.
谢什么
For what?
把我从大门外救回来
For getting me out there that day,
收留我
taking me in.
如果你没有婴儿奶粉
Well, if you didn't have that baby formula,
我也不会救你的
I wouldn't have.
你本可以只拿走奶粉的
You could have just taken the formula.
好吧
Well…
那可能就是因为别的了
must have been something else, then.
是卡尔的决定
You know, it was Carl who made the call.
他说你属于这里
He said you belonged here.
你是我们的一员
You're one of us.
要记住 他们在那里杀了我们八个同胞
Remember, they killed eight men back there.
在这里杀了五个
Five here last time.
他们与丧尸无异
They're no different from the biters.
他们不把我们全部杀掉是不会收手的
They're not gonna stop until they kill us all,
夺走我们的辛勤成果
taken everything we've worked so hard for.
我们要彻底做个了结
We're gonna end this once and for all.
总督
Governor.
这话很难说出口
This ain't easy to say.
我们不参加这次行动
You're gonna have to count us out.
这不是我们的战争
This isn't our fight.
我们只和行尸作战
We'll fight against the biters,
而不是无辜的人
not other people.
我们留在这 保护孩子们
Now we'll stay here and defend the children.
你们回来后 如果想让我们走
When you return, if you want us gone,
我们不会有怨言
no hard feelings.
谢谢
Thank you.
出发
Let's roll!
前进
Go!
走 快走
Go, go! Move!
快 快 快点
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
（行善者复活得生 作恶者复活定罪）
给我个手电
Give me a flashlight.
我们分头行动 你带一队去那边
Let's split up. You take a group that way.
你带一队 跟着我
You, bring a group, follow me.
走
Go.
米尔顿
Milton?
我捡工具的时候
When the tools dropped,
把几把钳子留在你身后的地上了
I-I left some pliers on the floor behind you.
如果你能
If you can drag…
如果你能把右脚伸过去 就能拿到
if you can drag your right foot back, you… you can get them.
对了
That… that's it.
- 天啊 - 快了
- Oh, God. - Almost.
我会救咱俩出去
I'm gonna get us both out of here.
你会没事的
And you're gonna be okay.
你把锁铐打开之后
Now when… when you get free,
就去找些锋利的东西
you are going to find something very sharp…
插进我的脑袋
and you are going to stab me in the head.
这才是你要做的事
That is what you are going to do.
加油
Keep trying-
快过来
Come on.
那边
Over there.
什么声音
What was that?
这边走
This way.
我们在南墙那边干掉几个行尸
We took out a few biters on the south wall.
除此以外 很平静
Other than that, everything's quiet.
下一班我来
I'll get the next one.
你觉得当他们回来之后会发生什么
What do you think happens when they return?
我们得悄悄溜出去 安德莉亚就成功了
We might have to slip out. Andrea made it out.
如果跑去监狱 还不如不跑
If she's at the prison, it didn't do her any good.
我去去就回
I'll be right back.
- 轮到我了 - 呆着别动
- It's my turn. - Stay put.
我去
I got it.
拿到了 拿到了
I got it. I got it.
米尔顿
Milton?
Milton.
为什么你还一直留在这
Why did you stay…
你明明已经知道你的朋友在外面
after you found out your friends were out there?
我不想放弃任何人的生命
I wanted to save everyone.
甚至是总督的
Even the Governor for a while.
我有机会杀掉他
I had a chance to kill him.
为什么你最终没有动手
What stopped you?
你知道的 我当时还很犹豫
You know, this was before.
他在睡觉 我有一把刀子
He was asleep. I had a knife.
但我还是试着用其他方法阻止事情的发生
But I tried to stop it all another way…
因为我不希望任何一个人死掉
because I didn't want anyone to die.
我还在这里
I'm still here.
我还活着
I'm still alive.
没错
Yeah.
你还活着
You are.
你得快一点
You need to hurry.
是的
Right.
好的
Okay.
趴在地上
Hold your ground!
（快跑）
离开这里
Get the hell out of here!
我应该在那里
I should be there.
走
Go.
- 走 - 快跑
- Move! - Go. Go, go, go. Go.
前进
Move! Move!
开火 开火
Hit it, hit it, hit it!
枪坏了
It's not working.
快
Go, man!
见鬼 卡壳了
Shit. It's jammed!
- 回来
- Return…
我们没胜算 快走
They're not going anywhere. Come on.
成功了吗
We did it?
成功了
We did it.
下来
Come on down.
别开枪
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Don't shoot.
放下武器 孩子
Drop the weapon, son.
好
Sure.
给你
Here, take it.
我们成功了 赶走了他们
We did it. We drove them out.
我们应该乘胜追击
We should go after them.
我们应该结束战斗
We should finish it.
已经结束了
It is finished.
你没看见他们逃跑了吗
Didn't you see them hightail it out of here?
他们会再来的
They could regroup.
我们不能冒险
We can't take the chance.
总督不会停止的
He's not gonna stop.
他们说得对
They're right.
我们不能活在恐惧中
We can't keep living like this.
我们要攻击伍德伯里吗
So we take the fight back to Woodbury.
上次我们差点都没回来
We barely made it back last time.
我不在乎
He don't care.
好
Yeah.
- 我们查查其他人 - 走
Let's check on the others.
- 嘿 - 爸爸 我要去伍德伯里
- Hey. - Dad, I'm coming to Woodbury.
- 卡尔 - 爸爸 我刚完成了自己的任务
- Carl. - Dad, I did do my job out there.
跟你们一样
Just like all of you.
我杀死了一个总督的小兵
Took out one of the Governor's soldiers.
总督的小兵
One of his soldiers?
他只是个逃命的孩子
A kid running away?
不巧遇见了我们
He stumbled across us.
不对 他是要耍花招
No, he drew on us.
对不起 让你面对这种事
I'm sorry you had to do that.
我只是尽了本份而已
It's what I was there for.
我和你一起去
I'm going with you.
那个孩子被吓坏了
That kid was scared.
他正打算缴枪
He was handing his gun over.
卡尔说他是要耍花招
He said he drew.
卡尔说他只是在自卫
Carl said it was in defense.
我亲眼目睹 他不必开枪
I was there. He didn't have to shoot.
完全没有理由开枪
He had every reason not to…
或许你只是被表面迷惑了
Maybe it looked like that to you, Hershel…
瑞克
Rick!
我再说一次
I'm telling you.
他打死了那孩子
he gunned that kid down.
靠边停车
Move over!
把卡车给我停下
Hey! I want this truck over.
快 快
Go. Pull in front of them.
你们他妈的到底在干嘛
What the hell are you doing?
我们要赶尽杀绝
We need to dig in.
不值得冒这个险
It's not worth it.
这是大屠杀
That was a slaughter.
你们这些没种的
You bunch of pussies.
我早说过应该咱几个自己动手
I told you we should have handled this shit ourselves.
我们不想再争这破监狱了
We're done fighting for a hole with a half dozen.
那里面住了一群疯子
psychopaths living in it.
就让他们住那儿算了
They can keep it.
你也看到了 他们想杀了我们
You've seen what they've done… attacked us.
他们杀了我儿子 我们要杀回去
They killed my boy. We're going back.
我们不是当兵的
We are not soldiers.
你要我们杀行尸 那没问题
Want us to kill biters, of course.
但这就太疯狂了
But this is crazy.
回家吧
Go home, then.
你以为你回去就安全了吗
You think you're gonna be safe?
我要回伍德伯里
I'm going back to Woodbury.
我们来这根本不是解决恩怨的
We're not here to settle a grudge.
过来啊
Come on.
好了
Okay. Okay.
Okay. All right.
你还没死
You're still here.
你还活着
You're still alive.
好了
All right.
糟糕
Shit!
好
All right.
好了 好 拿到了
All right. Okay.
米琼恩
Michonne.
赫谢尔告诉我你打死那男孩的事了
Hershel told me about the boy you shot.
他拿着枪
He had a gun.
他是不是正在缴枪
Was he handing it over?
- 他之前刚袭击了我们 - 没错
- He had just attacked us. - Yeah.
是的 确实
Yes, he had.
他是不是正在缴枪
Was he handing it over?
这个险我不能冒
I couldn't take the chance.
我没打死咬死了戴尔的那只行尸
I didn't kill the walker that killed Dale.
看看都发生了什么
Look what happened.
儿子 这不是一回事
Son, that is not the same thing.
你没杀安德鲁
You didn't kill Andrew.
结果他回来害死了妈妈
and he came back and killed Mom.
你和总督在一个屋子里的时候
You were in a room with the Governor.
你没杀了他
and you let him go.
结果他杀了莫尔
And then he killed Merle.
我做了我必须做的
I did what I had to do.
去吧
Now go.
别让他再害死我们的人
So he doesn't kill any more of us.
瑞克 我们留下
Rick, we're staying.
我们不知道总督在哪儿
We don't know where the Governor is.
如果他回来 我们来抵御他
If he comes back, we'll hold him off.
就我们三个吗
Just the three of us?
好的
All right.
谢谢你们留下来
I appreciate you staying.
应该的
Sure.
快开 快开
Come on, come on.
好了 别慌
Come on. Come on.
不 快开啊
Okay, Okay-
放开我
Oh! Come on!
泰尔西
Tyreese!
- 是我 别开枪 - 趴下
- It's me! Don't… - Get down!
凯伦
Karen!
凯伦 你没事吧
Karen, are you okay?
- 我没事 - 总督人呢
- I'm fine! - Where's the Governor?
他见人就开枪
He fired on everyone.
把大家都杀光了
He killed them all.
你怎么跟他们在一起
Why are you with them?
他们救了我
They saved me.
我们要出来了
We're coming out!
We're coming out.
你们来这儿干嘛
What are you doing here?
我们本来是要来个了断的
We were coming to finish this.
可我们看到了总督干的好事
until we saw what the Governor did.
他把他们都杀了
He… he killed them?
是啊
Yeah.
凯伦说安德莉亚翻过了墙
Karen told us Andrea hopped the wall.
朝监狱去了
going for the prison.
可她没平安到达
She never made it.
她可能还在这儿
She might be here.
这就是他关押格兰和玛姬的地方
This is where he had Glenn and Maggie.
总督把人关在这儿
The Governor held people here?
他不只是关押他们
He did more than hold them.
能开门吗
Will you open it?
一 二
One, two…
安德莉亚
Andrea!
我本想阻止他们
I tried to stop them.
你发高烧了
You're burning up.
朱迪思 卡尔
Judith, Carl,
你们其他人
the rest of them…
我们
Us.
你也属于我们
The rest of us.
大家还活着吗
Are they alive?
没事 都活着
Yeah, they're alive.
幸好你找到了他们
It's good you found them.
如今没人能独自生存
No one can make it alone now.
我从来都不行
They never could.
我只是不想让任何人死去
I just didn't want anyone to die.
- 我能自我了断 - 不行
- I can do it myself. - No.
我必须这么做
I have to.
趁我还有意识
While I still can.
拜托
Please?
我知道保险栓怎么开
I know how the safety works.
我就留在你身边
Well, I'm not going anywhere.
我尽力了
I tried.
的确
You did.
你的确尽力了
怎么回事
What is this?
他们要加入我们的队伍
They're gonna join us.